# **Yassine Benchekroun**

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Yassine is a software developer and architect specializing in data science, machine learning, and AI. He has extensive experience in the end-to-end process of conceiving, designing, developing, and deploying data applications for large companies and startups.

# **SKILLS**

# • Libraries/APIs

PyTorch, XGBoost, Scikit-learn, Pandas, Matplotlib, Beautiful Soup, TensorFlow, Keras, SciPy, NumPy, Gradio, SpaCy, jQuery, React, HTMX

## Tools

Rasa.ai, Apache Airflow, Jupyter, GitHub, Git, ChatGPT, Haystack, Sublime Text, GitLab CI/CD, Tableau, PyCharm, IBM Watson, Pytest, Yahoo! Finance

# Languages

Python, SQL, ABAP, Java, R, JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, React, Next

# Frameworks

LightGBM, Django, Scrapy, Flask

# Paradigms

ETL, Continuous Integration (CI), Continuous Deployment, Test-driven Development (TDD), REST, Scrum

# Platforms

Docker, Google App Engine, MacOS, Linux, Google Cloud Platform (GCP), Kubernetes, Oracle, Apache Kafka, AWS Lambda, Amazon Web Services (AWS), Vercel, Azure, Blockchain

#### Storage

Data Pipelines, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Elasticsearch, PostGIS, MongoDB, Data Lakes, Google Cloud

### Other Skills

Data Analytics, Chatbots, Artificial Intelligence (AI), Data Analysis, Statistical Data Analysis, Natural Language Processing (NLP), Data Engineering, Data Science, Machine Learning, SAP, Natural Language Understanding (NLU), Generative Pre-trained Transformer 3 (GPT-3), Generative Pre-trained Transformers (GPT), Text Generation, FastAPI, Language Models, Machine Learning Operations (MLOps), Large Language Models (LLMs), Analytics, Data Scientist, Predictive Analytics, Data Modeling, Generative Artificial Intelligence (GenAI), Image Processing, Serverless, Recommendation Systems, Ixml, Web Scraping, Deep Learning, Scientific Computing, Computational Linguistics, OpenAI, LangChain, Technical Leadership, Software Architecture, Full-stack, Llama 2, OpenAI GPT-4 API, Supervised Learning, Unsupervised Learning, Retrieval-augmented Generation (RAG), Supervised Machine Learning, Data Mining, Web Development, Fraud Prevention, Software as a Service (SaaS), Algorithms, Statistics, A/B Testing, Statistical Modeling, Outlier Detection, Cloud, Forecasting, Time Series, Big Data, Maps, OCR, Data Warehouse Design, Google BigQuery, Computer Vision, Games, Optimization, AIOps, Supabase, Product Management, Web3, Architecture, Data Visualization, Dashboards, Finance

# **WORK HISTORY**

# AI Architect | Solvent.Life Ltd

02/2021 - 05/2024

- Designed and developed an LLM pipeline for an AI assistant in financial markets.
- Implemented advanced charting for financial market data, integrated with the AI assistant.
- Defined the architecture for the application and cloud deployment in Google.

# Machine Learning Engineer | Hum Nutrition Inc

02/2019 - 01/2021

- Developed a dynamic website for the company to present its product to clients and sell wardrobes.
- Created the web design and implemented it using React and Next.js.
- Built the back end for book appointments, brochure downloads by filling in client data, and a contact form using third-party packages.

# Full-Stack Developer | Site Matrix, LLC

09/2017 - 01/2019

- Developed REST API web huge app using Django. Implemented user auth services using JWT and Postgres as a database.
- Delivered microservices to retrieve domain data from domain management systems and trade domains based on that information.
- Developed the front end from scratch using React.
- Delivered async task management in Django using Celery and RabbitMQ.
- Added new features into a web app in the front and back end using Django and React.
- Tested apps using pytest and performed manual tests on the apps' front-end.
- Created a task management system to look at task running results from the admin panel.

#### **EDUCATION**

University of Al-Qadisiyah 05/2018

Bachelor's degree: Computer engineering

Mohammed V high school 05/2014

**Diploma(3 years)**: Computer Science

# **LANGUAGE**

• English : Fluent

• **Arabic**: Native or Bilingual